<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Zieffler on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Andrew Zieffler on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Ethan!</title>
      <link>/post/congratulations-ethan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/congratulations-ethan/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Ethan Brown, one of our Statistics Education students successfully defended his dissertation today! His dissertation research looked at how a sequence of structured activities impact students’ understanding about the Empirical Law of Large Numbers and sampling uncertainty. Ethan presented some of his preliminary analyses of this work at ICOTS 10 in Kyoto, Japan last year and received a commendation for that work [&lt;a href=&#34;https://iase-web.org/icots/10/proceedings/pdfs/ICOTS10_3H1.pdf&#34;&gt;read his paper here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-05-09-congratulations-ethan_files/IMG_2628.JPG&#34; alt=&#34;Ethan at the public part of his Final Oral Examination.&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Ethan at the public part of his Final Oral Examination.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The abstract for Ethan’s work is below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extensive research has documented students’ difficulty understanding and applying the Empirical Law of Large Numbers, the statistical principle that larger samples result in more precise estimation. However, existing interventions appear to have had limited success, perhaps because they merely demonstrate the Empirical Law of Large Numbers rather than support students’ conceptual understanding of why this phenomenon occurs. This dissertation developed a sequence of activities, Growing Certain, which provided support for two mechanistic explanations of the Empirical Law of Large Numbers for students in a simulation-based introductory statistics course: swamping, the decreasing influence of extreme values on the mean as sample size increases, and heaping, the increasing concentration of possible sample means around the population mean. Five students participated in over six hours of one-on-one clinical interviews of students, with analysis focused on one focal participant, “S”. S’s responses were analyzed using a detailed coding of S’s articulation of mechanism components. S already displayed strong inclination towards swamping in the pre-interview questions, and their articulation of swamping became more sophisticated as they progressed in Growing Certain. However, S’s understanding of the connections between population and sample were weak throughout, and S had a lot of difficulty reasoning about multiple sample means simultaneously in a sampling distribution. S’s lack of abstraction of the sample mean appeared to support them in attending to the dynamics of swamping, but hindered them in being able to reason about heaping. Future research could examine representations that bridge swamping and heaping, and to examine individual differences in attention to the mechanistic components of the Empirical Law of Large Numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV: Sale Items vs. Research Plan</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-06-cv-quotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-06-cv-quotation/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;Karen Kelsky writes about the importance of identifying a research plan and building your CV around this plan in her book &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Professor-Essential-Guide-Turning-Ph-D/dp/0553419420&#34;&gt;The Professor is In: The Essential Guide to Turning Your Ph.D. into a Job&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A reader once wrote to explain: During my years as a tenure track assistant professor, I went about publishing and doing research the way I do the grocery shopping: concentrating on the sale items like conferences, book reviews, on-line collaborations, i.e., all things that seemed “affordable.” As a result stock up on unnecessary items and find myself too tired to focus on the important things, those items that do not go on sale, but that are the nbuilding block of a good kitchen: articles and books. Although I have managed to publish quite a bit, I have squandered a lot of time and energy, because I did not have a clearly elaborated research plan. (p. 95)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I see this strategy of adding easy line items to the CV with many graduate students and early career professionals. This is not to say that giving talks and writing blog posts are worthless, they aren’t. But, as Roger Peng pointed out in &lt;a href=&#34;https://effortreport.libsyn.com/&#34;&gt;The Effort Report&lt;/a&gt;, if you think about your time, which is finite, as a pie chart, anything you do adds a “wedge” into your pie chart and by definition takes away area (time) from something else. If you have time constraints, it is better to optimize the time you spend, and for most academics that means focusing on scholarship, especially articles and books which are often weighted more in tenure and promotion decisions than other elements of scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advice Karen gives is solid; build a research agenda and then spend your time on things that matter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Awards! So Proud!</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-02-student-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-02-student-awards/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;On April 26, 2019, two of my Statistics Education graduate students, Chelsey Legacy and Vimal Rao, were given awards during the annual &lt;em&gt;Psychological Foundations and QME Awards and Recognition Ceremony&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://news.cehd.umn.edu/wp-content/uploads/2019/04/psych-foundations2-1-1024x684.jpg&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chelsey Legacy&lt;/strong&gt; (first row; right) was awarded the &lt;em&gt;Graduate Student Teaching Award&lt;/em&gt; for her incredible work in the EPsy 3264 classroom. &lt;strong&gt;Vimal Rao&lt;/strong&gt; (second row; second from right) was awarded the &lt;em&gt;Graduate Student Leadership Award&lt;/em&gt; for his work in building community. I am very proud of these students and these awards are an affirmation of their dedication and achievements in the program this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV Tips</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-01-cv-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-01-cv-tips/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;My colleague Joseph Rios and I helped organize a monthly reading and seminar series, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.google.com/umn.edu/qmereads/home&#34;&gt;QME and Friends Read&lt;/a&gt;, for interested graduate students in our program. In March, we hosted a seminar on the &lt;em&gt;Curriculum Vitae&lt;/em&gt;, or CV. In preparing for that seminar, I looked through many faculty and student CVs. I also read many blog posts, and scholarly work about putting together a CV. Based on all of this and my own expereiences and advice given to me, I decided to put together a post (maybe multiple posts) that includes some suggestions for compiling a CV.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;start-early-update-often&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Start Early; Update Often&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Start putting together your CV as &lt;em&gt;soon as you begin&lt;/em&gt; your graduate studies. Or, at the latest after your first term in graduate school. Update your CV after each term. In talking with faculty, many of my colleagues update their CV on a regular basis, for some this is monthly, for others weekly. The frequency will likely change as you progress through your academic career, and finding the right frequency is different for everyone. As such, the frequency is less important here than the regularity. Updating your CV is a scholarly habit that you will need to build. As you do more things, it is important to record them lest you forget and have to try and remember what you did three months ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;content-and-sequencing&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Content and Sequencing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What should be included in your CV? A CV is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themuse.com/advice/cv-vs-resumehere-are-the-differences&#34;&gt;different from a Resume&lt;/a&gt;. Curriculum Vitae literally means “course of life” and is meant to lay out the entirety of your academic life. This means that you will want to include information, among other things, on your:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Education&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic Appointments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teaching Experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic Honors and Awards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Publications
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Refereed Journal Articles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Book Chapters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conference Proceedings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Other Publications (e.g., Book reviews, blogs, non-refereed pieces)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Grants and Fellowships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Presentations
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Invited Presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Workshops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professional Service
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service to the Department, College, and University&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service to the Profession (e.g., journals you review for)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Service to the Community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you initially put your CV together, some of these categories may be combined. For example, you may not have any invited presentations/talks, so you might include a single heading of “Presentations”. Later in your career, as you accumulate invited talks, you may choose to categorize those entries under a separate sub-heading of “Invited Presentations”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sequencing of these headings varies, although typically “Education” and “Academic Appointments” are the first two things listed in the CV. After that, you might use the sequence of headings as an indication of importance. For example, since I am in a teaching-oriented position I include “Teaching Experience”&#34; and “Teaching Honors and Awards” before “Publications” and “Presentations”. If I were in a traditional tenure track position, I might reverse that. (Note that if you take a tenure-track position, many universities have a template for your CV that they want you to adhere to, including the sequence of categories.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;general-formattingtypography&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;General Formatting/Typography&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make your CV look good. It is the first impression other academics have of you as a professional if they have not met you in person. Consider the same set of publications in the figures below. The first figure below shows those publications written using the default font in Word (Calibri; ugh) and very little formatting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-05-01-cv-tips_files/unformatted-cv.png&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the same publications have been written using Bembo Standard, a readable serifed font. They have also been formatted and the links have been colored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2019-05-01-cv-tips_files/formatted-cv.png&#34; width=&#34;800&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Font matters. Formatting matters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;some-tips-for-different-sections&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Some Tips for Different Sections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I lay out some advice for different sections of the CV. These are not hard-and-fast rules, but are based on advice given to me and things I have picked up from reviewing many CVs (for annual student reviews, job candidates, etc.) over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;education&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Education&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is essentially a list of your degrees. List them from most recent to least recent. Give the year of completion, the institution and department for each degree. For example mine looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 10px; padding-left: 5px; border: 1px solid black; border-radius: 5px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDUCATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 90px;text-indent: -90px;&#34;&gt;
2006    &lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;University of Minnesota.&lt;/em&gt; Quantitative Methods in Education, Department of Educational Psychology
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 90px;text-indent: -90px;&#34;&gt;
1998    &lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Saint Cloud State University.&lt;/em&gt; Mathematics Education
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a Ph.D. student, you may also provide your thesis advisor (and also the thesis title if you are ABD). For example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 10px; padding-left: 5px; border: 1px solid black; border-radius: 5px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDUCATION&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 90px;text-indent: -90px;&#34;&gt;
2020 (Anticipated)    &lt;strong&gt;Ph.D.&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;University of Minnesota.&lt;/em&gt; Quantitative Methods in Education, Department of Educational Psychology
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 85px;text-indent: -85px;margin-top:-15px;&#34;&gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Thesis:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A Longitudinal Investigation of the Development of College Students’ Reasoning About Bivariate Data&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 85px;text-indent: -85px;margin-top:-15px;&#34;&gt;
   &lt;strong&gt;Thesis Advisor:&lt;/strong&gt; Joan Garfield
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 90px;text-indent: -90px;&#34;&gt;
1998    &lt;strong&gt;B.S.&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Saint Cloud State University.&lt;/em&gt; Mathematics Education
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;publications-and-presentations&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Publications and Presentations&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any of the categories where you are including bibliographic entries, use the style that your profession uses to format these. For example, in Educational Psychology we use APA. So all of my publications and presentations are formatted using the APA style. Within each category, it is also helpful if you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Order the entries from most recent to least recent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold your name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Index each entry with a count. Make the oldest entry 1 and count forward in time. This has the advantage that you can easily find out how many entries you have by looking at the most recent, and also that you don’t have to re-number every time you add a new entry. (You will be amazed at how often you need to provide the counts of these things.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have authored a publication with your students, indicate that. I include a super-scripted dagger next to a students name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here for example is how I have listed my “Other Publications”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;margin-left: 10px; padding-left: 5px; border: 1px solid black; border-radius: 5px;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OTHER PUBLICATIONS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 45px;text-indent: -45px;&#34;&gt;
[5]  &lt;strong&gt;Zieffler, A.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Justice, N.† (2015). Teardowns, historical renovation, and paint-and-patch: Curricular changes and faculty development. Invited comment on G. Cobb, ‘Mere renovation is too little too late: We need to Rethink our Undergraduate Curriculum from the Ground Up’. &lt;em&gt;The American Statistician, 69&lt;/em&gt;(4). &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00031305.2015.1093029&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/00031305.2015.1093029&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 45px;text-indent: -45px;&#34;&gt;
[4]  Isaak, R., &lt;strong&gt;Zieffler, A.&lt;/strong&gt;, &amp;amp; Garfield, J. (2013). Response. &lt;em&gt;Technology Innovations in Statistics Education, 7&lt;/em&gt;(3). &lt;a href=&#34;http://escholarship.org/uc/item/8gq9t3c3&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://escholarship.org/uc/item/8gq9t3c3&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 45px;text-indent: -45px;&#34;&gt;
[3]  Gill, B., &lt;strong&gt;Zieffler, A.&lt;/strong&gt;, Boynton, N., Alberts, K. S., Humphrey, P., McKenzie, J., &amp;amp; Posner, M. A. (2012). Response to ‘Statistics à la Mode’. &lt;em&gt;AmStat News, February&lt;/em&gt;, x–xx. &lt;a href=&#34;http://magazine.amstat.org/blog/2012/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://magazine.amstat.org/blog/2012/&lt;/a&gt; 02/01/maa-response/
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 45px;text-indent: -45px;&#34;&gt;
[2]  Garfield, J., &amp;amp; &lt;strong&gt;Zieffler, A.&lt;/strong&gt; (2011). Response to: “Towards more accessible conceptions of statistical inference” by C. Wild, M. Pfannkuch, M. Regan and N. J. Horton. &lt;em&gt;Journal of the Royal Statistical Society. Series A, 174&lt;/em&gt;(Part 2), 280.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;padding-left: 45px;text-indent: -45px;&#34;&gt;
[1]  &lt;strong&gt;Zieffler, A.&lt;/strong&gt; (1999). A statistical journey with ninth grade students. &lt;em&gt;Math Times, Winter&lt;/em&gt;, 14.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing in the &#39;60s</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-30-computer-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-30-computer-brain/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;My dad was a mathematics teacher at Sartell High School and was also really into computing and programming. I remember learning BASIC with him on our Apple IIe and also programming our TI-99/4A. (To save a program on the TI, we had to hook up an external tape recorder and write to a cassette tape. Then to run the program, you played the tape!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://computermuseum.50megs.com/images/ti994a-box.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;TI-99&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Old issues of &lt;em&gt;Byte&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Compute&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Family Computing&lt;/em&gt; (check out the 1982 TV ad below), and other magazines and educational trades were stacked a mile-high in our living room; many providing the outlines of a program to create some graphical spectacle (e.g., a flashing Christmas tree or Jack-O-Lantern). Writing out the syntax to create these “masterpieces”, I began to learn how pixels on the computer screen could be manipulated to form images. I also experienced the anticipation of runnning the syntax only to have it fail because somewhere in the several 100 lines of code I just typed I missed a comma or semicolon, or mis-typed a digit…oh the drag of de-bugging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/w18SieyAZiM&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;
&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My dad and Dan Brockton (the Sartell librarian) were early advocates for teaching programming in the high school setting. They were also instrumental in bringing early computers into the school and getting students interested in using them. Below is an article that appeared in the high school paper about one of those computers, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sacatech.com/blog-Programma-101-the-first-personal-computer.php&#34;&gt;Programma 101&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;text-align:center;&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;../../static/img/new-brain-sartell.png&#34; width=&#39;400px&#39; alt=&#34;Programma 101&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several things that stand out from this article (not the least is the gendered use of language, although it was great to see at least one female in the picture).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of that thing was $2070.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It prints at a rate of 30 characters per second.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data was stored on a magnetic card.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apparently at that time, that machine looked complicated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deprecating Statistical Significance: Toward Better Science</title>
      <link>/post/2019-04-26-slhs-prosem/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-04-26-slhs-prosem/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;On Friday April 26, 2019 I gave an invited talk to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cla.umn.edu/slhs&#34;&gt;Department of Speech-Language-Hearing Sciences&lt;/a&gt; in their Pro-Sem series. These are really neat as they are organized by the graduate students. This is the third one of these I have given over the years and each is a treat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this talk I spoke about the ASA’s recent call for the deprecation of “statistical significance” and all its related variants (e.g., “significantly different,” “&lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05”, and “nonsignificant”, asterisks in a table). Citing articles in the recent volume of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/toc/utas20/73/sup1&#34;&gt;The American Statistician&lt;/a&gt; and drawing on the historical conflagration that is NHST I laid out why scientists and statisticians have an issue with “statistical significance” and also proposed some ideas for moving forward based on those proposed by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/full/10.1080/00031305.2019.1583913&#34;&gt;Ronald L. Wasserstein, Allen L. Schirm &amp;amp; Nicole A. Lazar&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The slides for the talk are available &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zief0002/website/raw/master/public/files/2019-slhs-prosem.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inbox Zero</title>
      <link>/post/2018-08-27-inbox-zero/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-08-27-inbox-zero/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;On Saturday August 25, 2018 at 8:08 PM I finally hit &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z9UjeTMb3Yk&#34;&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/inbox-zero.png&#34; alt=&#34;Inbox Zero&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I did it by immediately copying the snippets of email I wanted into Evernote notes (my notetaking system). I also attended to to-dos more immediately, or added them to a note of “To-Dos”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I doubt I will stay at zero emails in my inbox, but I have been at fewer than 10 emails all summer. Hoping to keep things at this level as the semester gears up.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Every Rose has It&#39;s Thorn: Secondary Teachers&#39; Reasoning about Statistical Models</title>
      <link>/publication/2018-zdm/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2018-zdm/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computing Talk at SSC 2018</title>
      <link>/post/ssc-computing-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/ssc-computing-talk/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;I am giving a talk at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ssc.ca/en/publications/ssc-liaison/vol-32-1-february-2018/ssc-2018-46th-annual-meeting-statistical-society&#34;&gt;46th Annual Meeting of the Statistical Society of Canada&lt;/a&gt; in Montreal on June 05, 2018. The talk is part of an invited session on &lt;em&gt;Teaching Statistics to Graduate Students in the Health and Social Sciences&lt;/em&gt;. Information, including the slides, is available below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Statistical Computing: Non-Ignorable Missingness in the Graduate-Level Social Science Curriculum&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; In 2010, Nolan and Temple Lang pointed out that &amp;quot;computational literacy and programming are as fundamental to statistical practice and research as mathematics&amp;quot;. Since that time computation has become an even more important skillset for researchers and scientists who use statistics. Many graduate-level statistics programs in the social sciences have yet to adopt statistical computing into the curriculum. Students either learn computing on their own or its teaching is relegated to specialty, often advanced, coursework. In either case, it is often only a small minority of quantitatively-focused students that are exposed to computing. The majority of graduate-level social science students, however, are not quantitatively focused. To what extent should they learn statistical computing? Which aspects of statistical computing should they be exposed to? In this talk, I explore these questions and offer some advice for teaching statistical computing to graduate-level social science students.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Slides:&lt;/strong&gt; Available at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zief0002/website/raw/master/public/files/computing-talk-2018-05-07.pdf&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zief0002/website/raw/master/public/files/computing-talk-2018-05-07.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Markdown Theme Gallery</title>
      <link>/post/r-markdown-theme-gallery/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/r-markdown-theme-gallery/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;R Markdown is a great way to integrate R code into a document. An example of the &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; theme used in R Markdown HTML documents is shown below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/default.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;pre-packaged-themes&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Pre-Packaged Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several other canned themes you can use rather than the &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt; theme. There are 12 additional themes that you can use without installing any other packages: “cerulean”, “cosmo”, “flatly”, “journal”, “lumen”, “paper”, “readable”, “sandstone”, “simplex”, “spacelab”, “united”, and “yeti”. You can read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rmarkdown.rstudio.com/html_document_format.html#appearance_and_style&#34;&gt;R Markdown documentation&lt;/a&gt; for detail about how to change your theme from the &lt;code&gt;default&lt;/code&gt;. Below are screenshots for each of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cerulean-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;cerulean&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/cerulean.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cosmo-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;cosmo&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/cosmo.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;flatly-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;flatly&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/flatly.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;journal-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;journal&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/journal.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;lumen-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;lumen&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/lumen.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;paper-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;paper&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/paper.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;readable-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;readable&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/readable.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;sandstone-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;sandstone&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/sandstone.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;simplex-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;simplex&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/simplex.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;spacelab-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;spacelab&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/spacelab.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;united-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;united&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/united.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;yeti-theme&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;yeti&lt;/code&gt; Theme&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/yeti.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;even-more-themes&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Even More Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are several add-on R packages that you can install to implement even more R Markdown HTML themes. For example &lt;a href=&#34;https://yixuan.cos.name/prettydoc/&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;prettydoc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/juba/rmdformats&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;rmdformats&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hrbrmstr/hrbrthemes&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;hrbrthemes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rstudio/tufte&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tufte&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://dirk.eddelbuettel.com/code/tint.html&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;tint&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Below I show screenshots of the themes from these packages as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;ipsum-theme-from-hrbrthemes-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;ipsum&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;hrbrthemes&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/hrbrthemes-ipsum.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;architect-theme-from-prettydoc-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;architect&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;prettydoc&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/prettydoc-architect.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cayman-theme-from-prettydoc-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;cayman&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;prettydoc&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/prettydoc-cayman.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;hpstr-theme-from-prettydoc-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;hpstr&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;prettydoc&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/prettydoc-hpstr.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;leonids-theme-from-prettydoc-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;leonids&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;prettydoc&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/prettydoc-leonids.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tactile-theme-from-prettydoc-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;tactile&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;prettydoc&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/prettydoc-tactile.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;html_clean-theme-from-rmdformats-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;html_clean&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;rmdformats&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/rmdformats-html_clean.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;html_docco-theme-from-rmdformats-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;html_docco&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;rmdformats&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/rmdformats-html_docco.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;material-theme-from-rmdformats-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;material&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;rmdformats&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/rmdformats-material.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;readthedown-theme-from-rmdformats-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;readthedown&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;rmdformats&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/rmdformats-readthedown.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tinthtml-theme-from-tint-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;tintHtml&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;tint&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/tint-tintHtml.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;tufte_html-theme-from-tufte-package&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;code&gt;tufte_html&lt;/code&gt; Theme (from &lt;code&gt;tufte&lt;/code&gt; Package)&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/rmarkdown-themes/tufte-tufte_html.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Weather in Minneapolis</title>
      <link>/post/spring-weather-in-minneapolis/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/spring-weather-in-minneapolis/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;It feels like this spring has been especially terrible weather-wise. We have gotten a lot of snow and it has been cold. To evaluate whether this is the case or whether I have hindsight bias, I pulled some historical weather data for the month of April from &lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Weather Underground&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;library(dplyr)
library(forcats)
library(ggplot2)
library(ggridges)
library(readr)
library(viridis)

# Read in data
april = read_csv(&amp;quot;~/Documents/github/Public-Stuff/data/april-weather.csv&amp;quot;)

# Filter dates
april = april %&amp;gt;%
  filter(date &amp;lt;= 11)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I grabbed data back to 2008 (avialable at &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zief0002/Public-Stuff/master/data/april-weather.csv&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/zief0002/Public-Stuff/master/data/april-weather.csv&lt;/a&gt;). To be fair about the comparisons I was making, I filtered the data
so that I only had the first eleven days of April for each year represented in the data. (April is a month in Minnesota that has a lot of variation from the first to last day of the month.) I then counted the number of those days each year that it snowed, as well as, the number of days over 40℉, 50℉, and 60℉.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;april %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(year) %&amp;gt;%
  summarize(
    days_with_snow = length(grep(pattern = &amp;quot;Snow&amp;quot;, x = events)),
    days_over_40 = sum(temp_high &amp;gt; 40),
    days_over_50 = sum(temp_high &amp;gt; 50),
    days_over_60 = sum(temp_high &amp;gt; 60)
  )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 11 x 5
##     year days_with_snow days_over_40 days_over_50 days_over_60
##    &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;          &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;        &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;        &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;        &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;
##  1  2008              4            7            3            2
##  2  2009              3           10            4            0
##  3  2010              0           11           11            7
##  4  2011              2           11            9            4
##  5  2012              0           11            9            6
##  6  2013              4            7            2            0
##  7  2014              3            8            6            4
##  8  2015              2           11            6            3
##  9  2016              3            8            2            1
## 10  2017              2           11           11            4
## 11  2018              5            1            0            0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This suggested that my snow hypothesis (we have had more snow this year) may be erroneous. But, we have had a couple large snows; maybe we had more snow on the days we actually had snow. To evaluate this, I computed the total amount of precipitation for the years it actually snowed during the first eleven days of April.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Get the case numbers for the days that &amp;quot;Snow&amp;quot; is in the event column
snow_days = grep(pattern = &amp;quot;Snow&amp;quot;, x = april$events)

# Compute the total amount of precipitation on the days with snow
april %&amp;gt;%
  filter(row_number() %in% snow_days) %&amp;gt;%
  group_by(year) %&amp;gt;%
  summarize(
    total_snow = sum(precip, na.rm = TRUE)
    )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;## # A tibble: 9 x 2
##    year total_snow
##   &amp;lt;int&amp;gt;      &amp;lt;dbl&amp;gt;
## 1  2008       0.96
## 2  2009       0.47
## 3  2011       0.08
## 4  2013       1.39
## 5  2014       0.81
## 6  2015       0.71
## 7  2016       0.06
## 8  2017       0.18
## 9  2018       0.82&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While more snow than the last couple years, 2018 doesn’t stand out as a banner April for the amount of snow. We will attribute this erroneous hypothesis to snow-blindness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, my “April = 🌡” hypothesis seems spot on. In 2018, so far, we have only had one day where the daily high temperatur was over 40℉. In the 10 years previous, almost all of the first eleven days of April hit over 40℉. This is compounded by the fact that the one day it went over 40℉, the temperature rose to a balmy 41℉!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I looked at the distribution of the average daily temperatures since 2008. This was inspired by a post I saw &lt;a href=&#34;https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/ggridges/vignettes/gallery.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://austinwehrwein.com/data-visualization/it-brings-me-ggjoy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;# Ridge plot of the distribution of average daily temperatures by year
ggplot(april, aes(x = temp_avg, y = fct_rev(factor(year)), fill = ..x..)) +
  geom_density_ridges_gradient(scale = 3, rel_min_height = 0.01, gradient_lwd = 1.) +
  scale_x_continuous(expand = c(0.01, 0)) +
  scale_y_discrete(expand = c(0.01, 0)) +
  scale_fill_viridis(
    name = expression(paste(&amp;#39;Temp. (&amp;#39;,~degree,&amp;#39;F)&amp;#39;,sep=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;)), 
    option = &amp;quot;C&amp;quot;
  ) +
  labs(
    title = &amp;#39;April Temperatures in Minneapolis&amp;#39;,
    subtitle = &amp;#39;Mean temperatures for the first 11 days in April&amp;#39;,
    x = expression(paste(&amp;#39;Average Daily Temperature (&amp;#39;,~degree,&amp;#39;F)&amp;#39;,sep=&amp;#39;&amp;#39;))
  ) +
  theme_ridges(
    font_size = 13, 
    grid = TRUE
  ) + 
  theme(
    axis.title.y = element_blank()
  )&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-04-11-spring-weather-in-minneapolis_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-4-1.png&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This also suggests that we are experiencing a less than tropical April in Minneapolis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class: Part IV</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-09-epsy-5271-part-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-09-epsy-5271-part-04/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;This post is the fourth (and last) in a series of blogposts in which I respond to questions from the students in the &lt;em&gt;Becoming a Teacher of Statistics&lt;/em&gt; course. In today’s posting I respond to questions that asked me for predictions about the future of statistics teaching and statistics education research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before I get into the Q&amp;amp;A, let me just state: Prediction is hard. Leland Wilkinson in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1198/004017008000000460&#34;&gt;The Future of Statistical Computing&lt;/a&gt; reminded us of this when he cited a prediction about computers that Andrew Hamilton made in a 1949 issue of &lt;em&gt;Popular Mechanics&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where a calculator like the ENIAC today is equipped with 18,000 vacuum tubes and weighs 30 tons, computers in the future may have only 1,000 vacuum tubes and perhaps weigh only &lt;span class=&#34;math inline&#34;&gt;\(1 \dfrac{1}{2}\)&lt;/span&gt; tons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, read my responses with caution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;given-your-experience-of-evolution-of-statistics-education-research-over-the-past-around-30-years-or-so-where-do-you-envision-stat-ed-research-to-be-say-in-the-ensuing-30-years-what-major-stumble-blocks-if-any-might-the-stat-educators-face-along-the-path-what-should-be-some-best-strategies-to-overcome-those&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Given your experience of evolution of Statistics Education research over the past around 30 years or so, where do you envision Stat Ed research to be, say in the ensuing 30 years? What major stumble-blocks, if any, might the stat educators face along the path? What should be some best strategies to overcome those?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My hope is that statistics education research will be breaking out of its infancy and statistics educators will be paying more attention to what the research is showing with regards to pedagogy and stduent learning. I also hope that the community of statistics education researchers has, by that time, begun to coalesce around a common research agenda.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My cynical answer is that we will be in the same place as we are right now, with too few statistics educators aware of the research that exists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reality will probably be somewhere between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I consider what challenges the research community faces, I can’t help but pause and think about how statistics education has changed over time, even in the last 10 years. Computing has played a major role in this change. This has led to curriculum changes and questions about how to incorporate computing into courses. How do you teach both the statistical and computing content together? How much computing do we teach? Which computing tools do we teach? I forsee these challenges only growing in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I answered this in the &lt;em&gt;Becoming a Teacher of Statistics&lt;/em&gt; class, Dennis Pearl asked me whether one issue for the research community is the pace at which technology is driving the pace of change. New computing tools (R packages, dashboards, etc.) are appearing every day. These tools are adopted (and just as quickly abandoned as the new tool comes along) before any research can possibly happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research moves slowly. It is not uncommon for the timeline of research to be two to three years to get a study together, obtain IRB approval, conduct the study, write up the results, and disseminate them to the community. This timeline is not compatible with the pace of technological change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know what the answer to this is, but my first thought is that companies like Google are doing research in this fast-paced world, so maybe we can learn from what they are doing. My second thought is that companies like Google often have very clear measurements (did a person click on an ad), and statistics education does not (what does it mean to learn computing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;just-like-20-years-ago-bayesian-inference-was-not-considered-something-to-be-taught-in-intro-stats-course-mcmc-and-computation-were-still-a-problem-do-you-think-there-is-something-that-is-overlooked-nowadays-that-could-have-a-potential-to-be-taught-in-the-future&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Just like 20 years ago Bayesian Inference was not considered something to be taught in intro stats course (MCMC and computation were still a problem), do you think there is something that is overlooked nowadays that could have a potential to be taught in the future?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another prediction question. 😩 This one is easier. Yes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the follow-up is: Like what? I’m not sure, but inevitably something will rear up. In the 1990’s, statistics education began to push toward teaching more conceptual understanding and away from the formulaic and dogged calculation of probability problems. Asa result, probability took on a much smaller role in the curricula developed during this time. Twenty years later, the rise of simulation-based approaches to statistical inference brings probability modeling right back to the forefront, albeit in a different manner than before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still am a bit skeptical about teaching Bayesian inference in an introductory course. The ideas yes; the methods no. While incredibly useful to an applied statistician and scientists, Bayesian calculations are not stright forward nor easy. Computing, of course, can make these quicker, but will students understand what they are doing? Or will it just be following recipes? Now teaching the big ideas behind Bayesian inference make perfect sense in an introductory course; the idea that combining prior beliefs with evidence (data) leads to updated beliefs. This makes a lot of sense to me. Having students reason about how thes posterior beliefs are impacted by the data when those prior beliefs are strong versus when they are weak can lead to great discussion of how we weigh evidence and what that means for drawing conclusion (and also why it is so hard to sway people’s opinions).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;there-are-many-foreign-students-coming-to-america-for-education-purpose-in-different-levels-high-school-college-and-graduate-level.-do-you-think-this-will-influence-the-curriculum-of-the-courses-offered-in-america&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;There are many foreign students coming to America for education purpose in different levels: high school, college and graduate level. Do you think this will influence the curriculum of the courses offered in America?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably not. The American education system has an inertia that is very difficult to change. Even oodles of research evidence seems to have very little impact on this system. I have a theory that this may be because adults (i.e., parents) have gone through and experienced the system, and there is a hindsight bias about that experience. “In my day we worked on algebra problems nonstop, so you should too.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might think that at least colleges and universities would be quicker to change. It turns out that here too the system is slow to change. Individuals have more autonomy to make changes in their clasrooms at this level, but the sytem as a whole seems to be stuck on a fulcrum of “what we used to do”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In statistics, the reformers have been asking for change in the introductory course for years, citing the changes in the high school curriculum and standards such as Common Core (or previous to that the NCTM mathemateics standards—which have been around since the 1980’s), with little result. So, I am not optimistic that an influx of foreign students will have an influence either.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics Education Research Seminar: Teaching Statistics from a Modeling Perspective</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-06-epsy-8271-announcement/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-06-epsy-8271-announcement/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;My colleague Robert delMas is teaching our doctoral-level research seminar, EPsy 8271 next fall, and it looks to be an interesting topic. The details about the course follow:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;epsy-8271-statistics-education-research-seminar-teaching-statistics-from-a-modeling-perspective-3-credits&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;EPSY 8271 | Statistics Education Research Seminar: Teaching Statistics from a Modeling Perspective (3 credits)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day/Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Fridays, 9:00 a.m.–11:30 a.m. (Fall 2018)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Location:&lt;/strong&gt; 220 Wulling Hall &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Instructor:&lt;/strong&gt; Robert delMas, Ph.D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This seminar will focus on research related to teaching introductory statistics through a modeling approach. Students will read and discuss:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scholarship related to the similarities and differences between mathematical and statistical models&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research conducted on the development of students’ (and teachers’) understanding of probability and statistics through modeling-based instructional approaches&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this process, students will learn about and critique research methods, critically examine research findings from studies, and consider implications for teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a capstone to the course, each student will produce a scholarly paper that explores, in more depth, a research area covered during the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more information, contact Robert delMas, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto::delma001@umn.edu&#34;&gt;delma001@umn.edu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class: Part III</title>
      <link>/post/2018-04-02-epsy-5271-part-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-04-02-epsy-5271-part-03/</guid>
      <description>
  &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/bracket.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This post is the third in a series of blogposts in which I respond to questions from the students in the &lt;em&gt;Becoming a Teacher of Statistics&lt;/em&gt; course. In today’s posting I respond to questions related to teaching.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;with-a-flipped-classroom-the-professor-tapes-their-lecture-and-has-students-view-the-video-online.-i-think-the-logical-extreme-of-this-is-that-at-some-point-certain-lectures-will-become-immensely-popular-or-polished-to-the-point-of-surpassing-local-professors-lectures.-could-you-see-the-flipped-classroom-evolving-to-the-point-of-removing-the-need-for-local-professors-to-record-themselves-given-certain-excellent-online-lectures&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;With a flipped classroom, the professor tapes their lecture and has students view the video online. I think the logical extreme of this is that at some point, certain lectures will become immensely popular or polished to the point of surpassing local professors’ lectures. Could you see the flipped classroom evolving to the point of removing the need for local professors to record themselves, given certain excellent online lectures?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Potentially. Although I hope not. In my experience, not every class emphasizes the same thing, so while there are some concepts that are consistent across courses, the “local” professors bring something unique to the class they are teaching. Maybe it is this variation that is important for the professor’s to capture, rather than re-inventing the wheel of trying to give a lecture on a common topic like OLS estimation, say. If professors could focus on how to build-on these pre-canned lectures, rather than spending time and effort re-inventing them, it seems like a better use of resources.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To play devil’s advocate for a minute, how do we know when we have hit the apex in video lectures? Is popularity a signifier of consenus of greatness? (Counterpoint: As of this writing, &lt;code&gt;@realDonaldTrump&lt;/code&gt; has 49.8 million followers on Twitter.) Or is it that we come to this conclusion once a really great statistician has produced a video on a particular topic (e.g., &lt;a href=&#34;https://lagunita.stanford.edu/courses/HumanitiesSciences/StatLearning/Winter2016/about&#34;&gt;Hastie and Tibshirani’s lectures on Machine Learning&lt;/a&gt;)?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was tried in the early 1960’s for introductiry statistics, when the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Continental_Classroom&#34;&gt;Continental Classroom&lt;/a&gt; broadcast a course in probability and statistics on NBC taught by Frederick Mosteller. They also developed a textbook and other materials to accompany the course. Students received credit by enrolling in the course through a local college or university, and successfully completing the course examinations, which were mailed out to participating institutions. Aside from instant name recognition, this course was also immensely popular; more than 75,000 students took the probability and statistics course for credit at 320 colleges—which was broadcast between 6:00–7:00AM. (About 1.2 million people viewed the course but did not take it for credit.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sixty-plus years later, many people have probably never heard of the &lt;em&gt;Continental Classroom&lt;/em&gt;, or haven’t thought about it in many decades. The content (which you can view at the American Statistical Association’s headquarters in Alexandria, VA) is, not surprisingly, out of date. In the Twitter age things go out of date quickly. Even when attempts to update content are made, it is still hard. There was a great series of approximately 30 videos recorded in 1989, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.amazon.com/Against-All-Odds-Statistics-episodes/dp/1559460911&#34;&gt;Against All Odds: Inside Statistics&lt;/a&gt;, that introduced topics in statistics. (These loosely corresponded with topics in David Moore’s &lt;em&gt;Introduction to the Practice of Statistics&lt;/em&gt; textbook.) By the early 2000’s these seemed quite dated. Although the videos were &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.learner.org/courses/againstallodds/unitpages/index.html&#34;&gt;updated in 2013&lt;/a&gt;, it is unclear how much the content changed. (Why are we still worrying about creating stem-and-leaf plots in 2018!??)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;in-your-catalst-paper-written-with-huberty-you-mention-that-after-school-computer-labs-can-be-a-potential-improvement-for-the-csi-courses-you-installed-in-minnesota-schools.-since-its-been-a-couple-years-have-you-seen-any-schools-take-you-up-on-this-idea-i-would-agree-that-more-one-on-one-time-with-a-teacher-may-be-more-beneficial-for-shyer-students.-especially-for-those-in-the-beginning-of-the-course-that-have-the-preconceived-notion-that-they-suck-at-mathematics-and-therefore-will-not-do-as-well-as-in-your-course.&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;In your CATALST paper written with Huberty you mention that after school computer labs can be a potential improvement for the CSI courses you installed in Minnesota schools. Since it’s been a couple years, have you seen any schools take you up on this idea? I would agree that more one-on-one time with a teacher may be more beneficial for shyer students. Especially for those in the beginning of the course that have the preconceived notion that they “suck at mathematics and therefore will not do as well as in your course”.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think many of the teachers make sure time is available after school for students to work on the computers with TinkerPlots™. What I don’t know is how many students take advantage of it. Many of them are involved in after-school activities, or have other obligations that keep them from making it into the lab after school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think what tends to be more important than the one-on-one time is the pedagogy used in the classroom. The educational research overwhelmingly suggests that pedagogy matters for student learning, and that students in student-centered classrooms outperform their counterparts in lecture-based courses. (This is especilly true for minority and disadvantaged students; see &lt;a href=&#34;https://college.unc.edu/2014/09/02/hoganstudy/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;do-you-change-your-material-andor-approach-when-teaching-intro-stats-to-high-schoolers-ap-or-college-in-the-schools-for-example-versus-teaching-it-to-undergrads-versus-grad-students&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Do you change your material and/or approach when teaching intro stats to high schoolers (AP or College in the Schools, for example) versus teaching it to undergrads versus grad students?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Great question. Let me preface my answer with saying that although I taught high school for four years, this was around 1998 (the Backstreet Boys and N’Sync were big) and I haven’t really taught that age-level since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From working with high school teachers, and from some recollection, the big difference is that when teaching a high school class, you have far more time than we do at the university/college level. High school courses tend to meet every day, while we only meet twice a week. This means you can allow more time for the concepts and skills to develop when teaching a high school course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The assessments are also generally far less high-stakes than they are at the college level. In college you may have one or two exams that make up almost all of your grade. In high school, it is not uncommon to have many assessment opportunities throughout a course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, material-wise, I would employ many of the same materials in the high school course that we do in the college course. But, I would supplement these with other activities and materials that build-on the ideas and give students opportunities to practice what they’ve learned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pedagogically, I would try to approach things the same way, including discussions and cooperative learning. I believe that learning takes hard work and it is the student’s responsibility. I can facilitate that learning, but it is ultimately up to the student to take on that hard work. The brain is a muscle that needs to be worked out. Like physical work outs, you need to build-up to larger “weights”. Focusing on the process, not the product, is also important as the goal (learning) is a long-term outcome. It may be harder to convinve a high school student that this process, which takes time, is worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Q&amp;A with Becoming a Teacher of Statistics Class: Part II</title>
      <link>/post/2018-03-30-epsy-5271-part-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-03-30-epsy-5271-part-02/</guid>
      <description>
  &lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/bracket.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34; /&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This post is the second in a series of blogposts in which I respond to questions from the students in the &lt;em&gt;Becoming a Teacher of Statistics&lt;/em&gt; course. In today’s posting I respond to questions related to several of the projects I have worked on over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;can-you-tell-us-a-little-about-your-aims-project-i-think-its-not-always-easy-for-everyone-to-apply-guidelines-in-order-to-change-their-behavior-in-any-context-but-your-aims-project-seems-to-fill-that-gap-for-stats-educators-that-is-it-explicitly-creates-educational-materials-aligned-with-gaise.-can-you-also-tell-us-about-some-of-the-difficult-decision-points-in-developing-your-materials&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Can you tell us a little about your AIMS project? I think it’s not always easy for everyone to apply guidelines in order to change their behavior (in any context), but your AIMS project seems to fill that gap for stats educators-that is, it explicitly creates educational materials aligned with GAISE. Can you also tell us about some of the difficult decision points in developing your materials?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow. You are making me think. I honestly haven’t thought about AIMS in a long time (I think we started writing these materials in 2005ish). At that time, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amstat.org/asa/education/Guidelines-for-Assessment-and-Instruction-in-Statistics-Education-Reports.aspx&#34;&gt;GAISE recommendations&lt;/a&gt; had just come out. Joan Garfield, my advisor and colleague, was the chair of the committee that wrote the GAISE college report. She was also the person that had transformed the curriculum in our undergraduate course (EPsy 3264) to what it was at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were two graduate students, myself and &lt;a href=&#34;https://wp.stolaf.edu/education/sharon/&#34;&gt;Sharon Lane-Getaz&lt;/a&gt;, who were teaching 3264 at that time. We actually would write the curriculum as we went, writing a lesson, teaching it and observing the other teach, and then meeting afterward in Joan’s office to re-vise the lesson and write the next one. It was a very invloved process, and, in those early iterations, a little rough.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the major decisions was to choose what topics would be included in the course and which wouldn’t. We also really switched the focus from calculation to conceptual understanding. The choice of software was also a decision point. &lt;a href=&#34;https://concord.org/about/staff/william-finzer/&#34;&gt;Bill Finzer&lt;/a&gt; was one of the project’s advsiors because we were pretty convinced that Fathom was the software we wanted to use in the course. (Although, looking back on the actual lessons, I think the materials are pretty software agnostic.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;how-much-biology-did-you-have-to-know-to-contribute-meaningfully-to-the-development-of-biosquare-or-are-you-just-an-expert-in-assessment-creation-who-applied-his-expertise-to-biology&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;How much biology did you have to know to contribute meaningfully to the development of BioSQuaRE? Or, are you just an expert in assessment creation who applied his expertise to biology?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thankfully, not much. My high school and undergraduate experiences in biology were only slightly better than those in chemistry (although I did really enjoy an environmental biology course I took). I primarily brought assessment development expertise to the project. The biology expertise (from others on the project) was primarily in ensuring that the items had a context related to biology, as the assessment itself was geared toward measuring students’ quantitative skills and knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;whats-next-for-the-catalst-project-is-there-hope-to-expand-it-to-other-universities-or-high-schools-outside-minnesota&#34; class=&#34;section level4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;What’s next for the CATALST project? Is there hope to expand it to other universities or high schools outside Minnesota?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Good question. In thinking about the current CATALST curriculum, we do not have explicit plans to expand to other institutions, but if there is a grass roots expansion, the more the merrier. My sense is that it would be a pretty good curriculum for high schools, but that many high school teachers are not aware of the its existence. (Perhaps we should do a workshop aimed at high school teachers at USCOTS next year…)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One way that we have thought about “growing” the curriculum is to write a Lab Manual for use with R. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www-math.bgsu.edu/~albert/&#34;&gt;Jim Albert&lt;/a&gt; taught CATALST with R to his students at Bowling Green when we first started the project many moons ago. I think this could be used as a skeleton for writing such a Lab Manual, but updating the syntax to use &lt;strong&gt;mosaic&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;tidyverse&lt;/strong&gt; functions. The one reason we have not done this yet is that I am unsure that R is the correct choice of software in an introductory statistics course for undergraduates. Inference is hard to learn. Inference and coding may be too much at that level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lately, there have been a few of us (loosely) thinking about what a CATALST-like course that emphasizes data science might look like. In the early days of CATALST, we had thought about more forward-thinking units such as prediction/classification, and visualization. These were ultimately scrapped, but in today’s climate might be good candidates for a data science-driven curriculum. We would keep the pedagogical approach used in the CATALST course (cooperative learning, teacher as guide-on-the-side, discussion) and update the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
