<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Zieffler on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Andrew Zieffler on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>AIMS Project</title>
      <link>/project/aims-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/aims-project/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The NSF-funded project &lt;em&gt;Adapting and Implementing Innovative Material in Statistics (AIMS)&lt;/em&gt; developed lesson plans and activities based on innovative materials that have been produced for introductory statistics courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AIMS materials are available on Github at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zief0002/aims&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zief0002/aims&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The case for substantial change in statistics instruction is built on strong synergies between content, pedagogy, and technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;&lt;cite&gt;David Moore&lt;/cite&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Written in 2005&amp;ndash;2006, the AIMS lesson plans and student activity guides were developed to help transform an introductory statistics course into one that is aligned with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amstat.org/education/gaise/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education (GAISE)&lt;/a&gt; for teaching introductory statistics courses. The lessons, which build on implications from educational research, involve students in small and large group discussion, computer explorations, and hands-on activities. The lessons are described in full detail along with the research foundations for the lessons, in Garfield and Ben-Zvi&amp;rsquo;s book &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springer.com/us/book/9781402083822&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Developing Students&amp;rsquo; Statistical Reasoning: Connecting Research and Teaching Practice&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;aims-amp-gaise&#34;&gt;AIMS &amp;amp; GAISE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The AIMS materials have been aligned with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amstat.org/asa/education/Guidelines-for-Assessment-and-Instruction-in-Statistics-Education-Reports.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;2005 Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education (GAISE) College Report&lt;/a&gt;. Each of the six recommendations from this report is listed below along with an indication of how the AIMS materials have been aligned with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emphasize statistical literacy and develop statistical thinking:&lt;/strong&gt; The AIMS materials help build students’ statistical literacy by having them read their text and complete study questions, and respond to literacy oriented assessment items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use real data:&lt;/strong&gt; The AIMS materials use data gathered from students (student survey data, body data) and analyze other real data sets of interest (e.g., college admissions data)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stress conceptual understanding rather than mere knowledge of procedures:&lt;/strong&gt; The AIMS materials focus on the nine big ideas (data, model, distribution, center, variability, comparing groups, samples, inference, and covariation), and develop them throughout the course. Students first encounter these ideas informally, and then as they revisit them, the materials aid in moving them to more formal understanding and reasoning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Foster active learning in the classroom:&lt;/strong&gt; The AIMS lesson plans suggest how teachers may guide students through activities where they are actively engaged in making and testing conjectures, working in small groups, explaining their reasoning, and learning together. The materials also incorporate versions of many innovative student activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use technology for developing conceptual understanding and analyzing data:&lt;/strong&gt; The AIMS materials use Fathom&amp;trade; for data analysis and exploration, Tinkerplots&amp;trade; to help students understand and reason about graphs, Sampling SIM to simulate data to make informal inferences, and several applets to illustrate abstract concepts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use assessments to improve and evaluate student learning:&lt;/strong&gt; Three free resources can be used to assess students&amp;rsquo; statistical reasoning: The ARTIST website, the ARTIST Item Database, and the ARTIST Topic Tests and CAOS tests. These are all located at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://apps3.cehd.umn.edu/artist/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ARTIST website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;people&#34;&gt;People&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many people involved in the AIMS Project. Many of them are listed below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIMS Principal Investigators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Joan Garfield (University of Minnesota)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert delMas (University of Minnesota)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andrew Zieffler (University of Minnesota)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIMS Contributing Author&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dani Ben-Zvi (University of Haifa)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIMS Staff&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Michelle Everson (University of Minnesota)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jared Dixon (University of Minnesota, Graduate Research Assistant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beng Chang (University of Minnesota, Graduate Research Assistant)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIMS Evaluator&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robert Gould (University of California, Los Angeles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AIMS Advisory Board&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beth Chance (California Polytechnic State University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;George Cobb (Mount Holyoke College)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bill Finzer (KCP Technologies)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cliff Konold (University of Massachusetts Amherst)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Robin Lock (St. Lawrence University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dennis Pearl (The Ohio State University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allan Rossman (California Polytechnic State University)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Scheaffer (University of Florida)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioSQuaRE</title>
      <link>/project/2018-02-21-biosquare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2018-02-21-biosquare/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;BioSQuaRE is an instrument, created via an HHMI grant, to assess the quantitative readiness of students planning on majoring in biology or the life sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2012, several PIs who had received grants from HHMI to implement institution-level curriculum projects wrote a proposal to write an assessment that could be commonly used to evaluate their curricular efforts. These PIs were from the following institutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Macalester&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bryn Mawr&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oberlin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;St. Olaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lewis and Clark, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Claremont Colleges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I joined this project shortly thereafter as an expert in assessment development. I also brought with me two graduate students, Laura Le and Laura Ziegler, who joined the project as research assistants. (Both Lauras continued to work on the project even after they graduated and matriculated into academic jobs.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://d2ihvqrbsd9p9p.cloudfront.net/contentAsset/image/19329a63-3049-4a0a-889f-3ef2fc9d18e0/fileAsset/inode/d71404c4-d89c-4547-8232-cd236fc4fd80/filter/Resize,Jpeg/jpeg_q/85/resize_w/1080&#34; alt=&#34;Q6 Phote&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p style=&#34;font-size:70%;&#34;&gt;Q6 group at Keck Science Center (Claremont, CA) Feb. 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took several years to develop what is now BioSQuaRE (v.5). AFter the initial work to develop items, there were many iterations of piloting, data analysis, and assessment-revision. The current iteration of the assessment includes 29 items that cover content related to: (1) Algebra, functions, and modeling; (2) Statistics and probability; and (3) Visualization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we hope that results from BioSQuaRE can be used to address and evaluate curricular change in biology and life science courses. For more technical detail about the development of BioSQuaRE, see:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanhope, E., Ziegler, L., Haque, T., Le, L., Vinces, M., Davis, G. K., Zieffler, A., Brodfuehrer, P., Preest, M., Belisky, J., Umbanhowar, Jr., C., &amp;amp; Overvoorde, P. J. (2017). &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pubmed/29196427&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Development of a Biological Science Quantitative Reasoning Exam (BioSQuaRE).&lt;/a&gt; CBE–Life Sciences Education, 16(4), ar66. doi: 10.1187/cbe.16-10-0301&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;for-instructors&#34;&gt;For Instructors&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are an instructor interested in considering the use of BioSQuARE with your students, please complete this brief &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSevIoHPbU3CQSX2Jal3QTbudNU1rvAfj_evNyK1TOkWNj0UZw/viewform?usp=sf_link&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;online survey&lt;/a&gt;, which gathers some basic contact information (e.g., institutional type, departmental listing, class size, range of students, etc.). One of the BioSQuARE team will then follow-up with additional information and instruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will provide faculty liaisons with a report that summarizes the responses of their students. Please note, these summaries will be aggregated to the course or institution level and will only be provided if the number of students completing BioSQuaRE is large enough to protect individual students&amp;rsquo; anonymity. We also show comparisons of your average course performance to the averages of all students who have completed the instrument.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CATALST Project</title>
      <link>/project/catalst-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/catalst-project/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Change Agents for Teaching and Learning Statistics (CATALST)&lt;/em&gt; was an NSF-funded project that developed materials for teaching a radically different introductory statistics course based on randomization and bootstrap methods to provide students a deep understanding of statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The materials were turned into a free, online book, &lt;em&gt;Statistical Thinking: A Simulation Approach to Modeling Uncertainty&lt;/em&gt;, available at: &lt;a href=&#34;http://zief0002.github.io/statistical-thinking/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;http://zief0002.github.io/statistical-thinking/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The data sets and PDF version of the lab manual are available at the book&amp;rsquo;s Github repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/zief0002/statistical-thinking&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://github.com/zief0002/statistical-thinking&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>College in the Schools</title>
      <link>/post/2018-02-19-college-in-the-schools/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018-02-19-college-in-the-schools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ccaps.umn.edu/college-in-the-schools&#34;&gt;College in the Schools&lt;/a&gt; is a concurrent enrollment program in which existing University of Minnesota courses are taught in high schools by high school teachers. All schools wishing to offer a CIS course go through an application process, including an interview and approval by the post-secondary academic department sponsoring the course of any high school teachers who will be teaching the course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since CIS is a concurrent enrollment program, students are enrolled simultaneously in the University of Minnesota course (&lt;em&gt;EPsy 3264: Basic and Applied Statistics&lt;/em&gt;) and a course at their high school. (As such, they receive two separate grades.) This setup allows for variation between the university and high school schedules. It also allows high schools to cover additional material or devote additional time to topics as needed (e.g., to accommodate requirements of state testing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;cis-statistics&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CIS Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We implemented the CIS statistics course in the 2015–2016 academic year. Since that time, we have had 17 high schools teach a CIS statistics course. The map below shows these schools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2018-02-19-college-in-the-schools_files/figure-html/unnamed-chunk-1-1.png&#34; width=&#34;500px&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;curriculum-pedagogy-and-assessment&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Curriculum, Pedagogy, and Assessment&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To meet the University of Minnesota requirements, the high school students experience the same curriculum and assessments that is used at the university. (They are also graded using the same standards as students at the university.) The course uses the &lt;a href=&#34;https://priceless-wiles-535968.netlify.com/post/catalst-project/&#34;&gt;CATALST curriculum&lt;/a&gt; which immerses students in the nuts-and-bolts of statistical inference from the first day of the course via a focus on modeling and simulation. One of the primary goals of the CATALST curriculum is the promotion of statistical thinking. This is achieved by emphasizing the “core logic of statistical inference” throughout the curriculum, rather than procedural knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The underlying philosophy of CATALST is that students are primarily responsible for their own learning. Students meet that responsibility by reading the materials, completing the homework, and carrying out any other preparation prior to each class period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also true in the classroom, where students work with 2–3 other students through a series of structured activities and discussions. This group-work is where a majority of the student learning takes place. In the classroom, the role of the instructor is more “guide-on-the-side”: leading larger classroom discussions, posing questions, and helping students draw connections and make sense of the material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students use the &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinkerplots.com/&#34;&gt;TinkerPlots™ software&lt;/a&gt; during class and as a part of their at-home preparation and homework. TinkerPlots™ employs allows students to create models and simulate date using an interactive set of tools. The visual display of the simulation process helps students gain a deeper conceptual understanding of the underlying data generation process used in statistical inference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of the emphasis on cooperative group learning in the course, students are evaluated using both group and individual assessments. Individual-level assessments offer students an opportunity to show they have learned the material, while group assessments push students’ understanding of the course material through questions that extend the content in ways they may not have previously encountered (while at the same time offering these extensions via the relative safety of the group).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;professional-development&#34; class=&#34;section level3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Professional Development&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High school teachers who are accepted to teach the CIS course engage in ongoing professional development (PD). Each year they are required to complete 30 hours of PD: a 3-day workshop each summer and and a 1-day workshop in both the fall and spring semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to the PD, CIS teachers are also observed by University of Minnesota faculty. These observations occur at least once during the initial year that a school adopts a CIS course and at least once every three years thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;resources&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More information about the CIS statistics course and the CATALST curriculum can be found in the following resources:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Garfield, J., delMas, R., &amp;amp; Zieffler, A. (2012). Developing statistical modelers and thinkers in an introductory, tertiary-level statistics course. &lt;em&gt;ZDM—The International Journal on Mathematics Education, 44&lt;/em&gt;(4), 883–898.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zieffler, A., &amp;amp; Huberty, M. (2015). A catalyst for change in the high school math curriculum. &lt;em&gt;CHANCE, 28&lt;/em&gt;(3), 44–49. doi: 10.1080/09332480.2015.1099365&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello</title>
      <link>/post/hello/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hello/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development of a Biological Science Quantitative Reasoning Exam (BioSQuaRE)</title>
      <link>/publication/2017-biosquare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2017-biosquare/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the latest demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start guide&lt;/a&gt; or take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-default.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-default.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-ocean.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-ocean.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-dark.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-dark.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-forest.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-forest.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-1950s.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-1950s.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics graduate teaching assistants&#39; beliefs, practices, and preparation for teaching introductory statistics</title>
      <link>/publication/2017-serj/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/2017-serj/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Statistics graduate teaching assistants&#39; beliefs, practices, and preparation for teaching introductory statistics</title>
      <link>/publication/_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/_example/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2015 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;r-markdown&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;summary(cars)
##      speed           dist       
##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  
##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  
##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  
##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  
##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  
##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00
fit &amp;lt;- lm(dist ~ speed, data = cars)
fit
## 
## Call:
## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)
## 
## Coefficients:
## (Intercept)        speed  
##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;including-plots&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;par(mar = c(0, 1, 0, 1))
pie(
  c(280, 60, 20),
  c(&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;),
  col = c(&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;, &amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;),
  init.angle = -50, border = NA
)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/post/2015-07-23-r-rmarkdown_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;
Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
