<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics Education on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>/tags/statistics-education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics Education on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/statistics-education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>USCOTS 2019</title>
      <link>/post/uscots-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/uscots-2019/</guid>
      <description>Last week I attended the United States Conference on Teaching Statistics. The biennial conference, which took place at Penn State, attracts statistics educators and statistics education researchers from across the world. It was a fantastic conference with keynotes from Jane Watson, Allen Schirm and Ron Wasserstein, John Kruschke, and Kari Lock Morgan.
I cajoled four of my graduate students (Jonathan Brown, Mike Huberty, Chelsey Legacy, and Vimal Rao) to tag along, and it was fun to see them interacting with the people and ideas presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Congratulations Ethan!</title>
      <link>/post/congratulations-ethan/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/congratulations-ethan/</guid>
      <description>Ethan Brown, one of our Statistics Education students successfully defended his dissertation today! His dissertation research looked at how a sequence of structured activities impact students’ understanding about the Empirical Law of Large Numbers and sampling uncertainty. Ethan presented some of his preliminary analyses of this work at ICOTS 10 in Kyoto, Japan last year and received a commendation for that work [read his paper here.
Ethan at the public part of his Final Oral Examination.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Awards! So Proud!</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-02-student-awards/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-02-student-awards/</guid>
      <description>On April 26, 2019, two of my Statistics Education graduate students, Chelsey Legacy and Vimal Rao, were given awards during the annual Psychological Foundations and QME Awards and Recognition Ceremony.
Chelsey Legacy (first row; right) was awarded the Graduate Student Teaching Award for her incredible work in the EPsy 3264 classroom. Vimal Rao (second row; second from right) was awarded the Graduate Student Leadership Award for his work in building community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>