<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Quotation on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>/tags/quotation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Quotation on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/quotation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Richard Hamming on the Teaching of Mathematics</title>
      <link>/post/richard-hamming-on-calculus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/richard-hamming-on-calculus/</guid>
      <description>The way mathematics is currently taught it is exceedingly dull. In the calculus book we are currently using on my campus, I found no single problem whose answer I felt the student would care about! The problems in the text have the dignity of solving a crossword puzzle &amp;mdash; hard to be sure, but the result is of no significance in life. Richard Hamming, Calculus and Discrete Mathematics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CV: Sale Items vs. Research Plan</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-06-cv-quotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-06-cv-quotation/</guid>
      <description>Karen Kelsky writes about the importance of identifying a research plan and building your CV around this plan in her book The Professor is In: The Essential Guide to Turning Your Ph.D. into a Job.
 A reader once wrote to explain: During my years as a tenure track assistant professor, I went about publishing and doing research the way I do the grocery shopping: concentrating on the sale items like conferences, book reviews, on-line collaborations, i.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>