<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Andrew Zieffler</title>
    <link>/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Andrew Zieffler</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AIMS Project</title>
      <link>/project/aims-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/aims-project/</guid>
      <description>The NSF-funded project Adapting and Implementing Innovative Material in Statistics (AIMS) developed lesson plans and activities based on innovative materials that have been produced for introductory statistics courses.
The AIMS materials are available on Github at https://github.com/zief0002/aims
 The case for substantial change in statistics instruction is built on strong synergies between content, pedagogy, and technology.
&amp;mdash;David Moore
 Written in 2005&amp;ndash;2006, the AIMS lesson plans and student activity guides were developed to help transform an introductory statistics course into one that is aligned with the Guidelines for Assessment and Instruction in Statistics Education (GAISE) for teaching introductory statistics courses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BioSQuaRE</title>
      <link>/project/2018-02-21-biosquare/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/2018-02-21-biosquare/</guid>
      <description>BioSQuaRE is an instrument, created via an HHMI grant, to assess the quantitative readiness of students planning on majoring in biology or the life sciences.
Background In 2012, several PIs who had received grants from HHMI to implement institution-level curriculum projects wrote a proposal to write an assessment that could be commonly used to evaluate their curricular efforts. These PIs were from the following institutions:
 Macalester Bryn Mawr Oberlin St.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CATALST Project</title>
      <link>/project/catalst-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/catalst-project/</guid>
      <description>Change Agents for Teaching and Learning Statistics (CATALST) was an NSF-funded project that developed materials for teaching a radically different introductory statistics course based on randomization and bootstrap methods to provide students a deep understanding of statistical inference.
The materials were turned into a free, online book, Statistical Thinking: A Simulation Approach to Modeling Uncertainty, available at: http://zief0002.github.io/statistical-thinking/.
The data sets and PDF version of the lab manual are available at the book&amp;rsquo;s Github repository: https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>